# Himanshu Agarwal



agarwal@heyhimanshu.com

+918428058621, +6586572548



linkedin.com/in/himanshu-agarwal-b2469015



## **Summary**

I am a software developer with 4 years of professional experience in python development and have a bachelor's in computer science. Currently a part of a cybersecurity company for which, I built an improved version of the django based product to fulfill the needs of the client. I am looking to continue working in the Software development field to further improve my skill set and to learn additional skills as well.

## **Experience**



# Senior Software developer (Singapore)

Scantist - Sep 2022 - Nov 2023

- working as SeniorBackend developer and responsible for making an improved version of the current product to make it an industry level product. Revamping the code base using PEP8 and SOLID principles.
- I also created automation tools using LLM APIs for the internal use of our organization which resulted in saving more working hours.
- worked heavily with LLM and integrated their 3rd APIs to our system. i also worked with GenAI.
- Created new Data Pipelines to reduce the API response time and make it more scalable. Created new REST APIs.
- I am using SQL and NOSQL databases like PostgreSQL, for cloud AWS and GCP, CI/CD pipelines, C#, Docker for containerization, GIT for version control, using React is in Frontend and Kubernetes on devops side while working in an Agile environment.
- Using Redis-celery for the server side cache and use of Async APIs to increase the user experience and reduce the response time.
- Dividing the single Diago project into multiple Apps to reduce load of the current application and introducing microservices architecture. Also writing Test cases using the Django library and using tools like postman, visual studios for debugging and troubleshooting.
- I am responsible for guiding 2 interns and their work product.
- My responsibilities also include Doing code review of other developers and improving the overall quality of the code base.
- I also wrote protocols which are to be followed in backend development.

## Software Engineer (Remote)

Netguru -(Contract) - Nov 2020 - Aug 2022(1 year 8 months)

Worked on multiple web applications mainly using Diango and Flask, moving application from monolith to microservices architecture, training client side of developers, Developed and managed API. using python as the primary language, Mainly used AWS, docker, git, GCP, redis-celery for python frameworks. worked under B2B contract



## Software Developer (India)

Amdocs -(Contract) - Sep 2019 - Nov 2020 (1 year 3 months)

- •Developed a Django-REST based Web-application for the global People-analytics team, used the MongoDB for the database management, designed the frontend using React, Bootstrap. Deployed it on AWS. Currently used by 13000 employees on a daily basis.
- •Developed a Flask based application to automate the process of getting the details of suitable candidates for specified roles from Linkedin. I used selenium, python, and Sqlite to make the project. Using this application organization saved \$50,000/year and reduced human effort by 3
- •Implemented a Django based web application to showcase Al-generated personalized learning for each employee, created a dashboard to keep track of the progress, set goals etc., using python, react to make this project, it is currently used by 17000 Indian employees. Deployed on AWS.

### Education



#### **Vellore Institute of Technology**

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science

2015 - 2019

# Skills

 $Python \bullet Django \bullet Flask \bullet SQL \bullet NO \ SQL \bullet Docker \bullet AWS \bullet Git \bullet Postgres \bullet Redis \bullet OpenAPI \bullet CI/CD \bullet REST \ API \bullet JavaScript \bullet LLM \bullet C\# \bullet GenAII$